<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>academic on Rohan Menon</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/academic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in academic on Rohan Menon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WISP</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/wisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/wisp/</guid>
      <description>The Wireless Identification and Sensing Platform (WISP) is an extension of standard RFID. RFID systems typically have two devices, a tag and a reader. When a tag is brought close enough to a reader, the tag wirelessly collects energy from the reader and can send back information. However, typically, tags are pretty limited in what they send. It’s usually only a unique identifier.
WISP devices are tags that can do more than standard RFID, performing computation and taking sensor readings on-board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonant</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/resonant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/resonant/</guid>
      <description>Resonant installed into a baseball cap with a heads up display
Recent advancements in machine learning and image processing mean that the ability of computers to see has improved drastically in the last 10 years. While sound is a crucial part of how most people experience their environments, computer hearing has not seen the same advancements. We aimed to develop algorithms to locate audio signals within 3D space as well as classify them into several relevant categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aquametric</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/aquametric/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/aquametric/</guid>
      <description>Aquametric version 1.0 mounted in Alplause Kill
Metrics such as stage height, conductivity, and temperature can provide valuable insight into ecological health and can also serve as predictors for events such as flooding. Traditionally, these metrics are measured either manually by a scientist or by large and expensive permanently installed stations. Unfortunately, human measurement reduces the possible frequency of data collection and traditional sensor stations require lots of infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
